从上一集的《终空》里我们得知
Previously on "Final Space"...
夜幕揭晓了自己其实是来自未来的奎恩？！
Nightfall reveals that she's Quinn? From the future?!
我的天哪
Whoa! Hot diggity!
而且  她对盖瑞很有意思
Also, she has a thing for Gary,
然而没空搞太空3P了
but there's no time for cosmic three-ways...
因为我们的队员们要去修补太空缺口
because our crew has a breach to close in space...
时间紧迫呐
and fast.
盖瑞  你还有2分钟氧气可用
Gary, you have two minutes of oxygen left.
咱能...
Can we...
换点高兴的话题吗？
change that to something more cheerful?
好的  盖瑞
Sure, Gary.
饼干
Cookies.
假装你在烤一大堆饼干吧
Act like you're baking a big batch of cookies.
盖瑞  还有两分钟饼干就要烤好了
Gary, the cookies will be done in two minutes.
哦... 好极了  我喜欢饼干
Oh... fantastic. I love cookies.
你烤的是什么饼干？
What kind of cookies we talkin' about?
奶油全麦饼干
Butter wheat crunch.
那个... 那个不能算饼干
That's... not a cookie.
你知道的  HUE  你知道的！
And you know that, H.U.E. You know that!
鸭嘴兽字幕组出品
翻译 + 专访听译 + 校对 + 压制：Kyl
Final Space - Chapter Eight
终空  第一季第八集
Sync & Correction by f1nc0 from Addic7ed.com
本字幕仅供学习交流  请于下载后24小时内删除
大家！
Crew!
或者说“把烂脾气的暴力薰心的
Or legion of murdering an irritatingly power-thirsty
矮子恶魔打成屁眼筛子军团”！
pint-sized imp into a plethora of buttholes!
你们准备好拯救地球了吗！
Are you ready to save the Earth?!
- 好啊！好极了！   - 好！好啊！
- Hooray! Oh, yeah! - Hooray! Hooray!
问题是  队长大人  你准备好了吗？
The question is, Captain, are you ready?
我早就准备好了！
I'm so ready!
好个大头鬼！我上哪拯救地球去？
I'm so not ready! How am I gonna save an entire planet?
我只是在尝试
I'm all for trying,
我们很可能最后都死翘翘了
but there's a high chance we're all going to die!
或多或少  这已经是做成的买卖了
Yes. It's more or less a done deal.
这一点都没安慰到我！
That's not comforting at all!
我能做到的  对吧？对吧？！哦  根本不可能的！
I can do this, right? Right?! Oh, this is impossible!
只要用心  就没有不可能的事
Nothing is impossible if we apply our minds to it.
HUE  你知道任何一种可以修补缺口的方法吗？
H.U.E., do we know of a way we can close this breach?
我不知道
No.
好吧  这就不好玩了
Well, that's not good.
或者... 你知道随便什么我们该做的事吗？
Okay, uh, well... anything at all we could do?
这我知道  你可以亲亲自己的脸蛋  和自己告别
Yes. You can kiss your cheeks goodbye.
你丫耍我？
You givin' me a little clap back?
你丫竟然耍我  HUE？！
You givin' me the old clap back, H.U.E.?!
在内爆成一团虚无之前  我们至少该试着做点什么
I thought I'd give it a try before we implode into nothingness.
他说“内爆成一团虚无”！
"Implode into nothingness," he said!
哦我的老天啊  大周一的
Oh, my gosh. Freaking Mondays.
- 盖瑞  我会死吗？   - 你是在给我振奋精神吗  KVN？
- Gary, am I gonna die? - Are you trying to cheer me up, KVN?
能看到你死真是太棒了
Okay, because you dying would be a wonderful development.
♪ 我们都将死去 ♪
♪ We're all gonna die ♪
♪ 我们都将死... ♪
♪ We're all gonna di... ♪
给我闭嘴  KVN  不然我会想办法让你闭嘴的
Shut the hell up, KVN. Or I will find ways.
其实还是有一种方法的
Actually, there is a way.
HUE  把目标定在12区  6.79域
H.U.E., set coordinates for sector 12, region 6.79.
夜幕  我们会直接冲进猎户星云
Nightfall, that would fly us directly into the sun
中央的主星的
at the heart of the Orion Nebula.
- 我知道   - 我们不能往那飞！
- I know. - We are not flying into a sun!
- 你想活下去吗？   - 我当然想
- Do you want to live? - Yes. I would love to live.
这也正是为什么我们不能往那里飞！
That's exactly freaking why we're not flying into a sun!
你说对了  我们不能飞进去  我们需要光折
You're right. We're going to lightfold in.
这更不靠谱了！你说得好像这个方法更好似的
That's freaking worse! You said it like it was better,
- 然而显然这个方法更烂！   - 我不建议这么干
- but that is the opposite of better! - I would never suggest this
除非你还知道什么我不知道的秘密
unless I knew something you're not sharing.
你还知道什么？
What do you know?
奎恩  你不好奇你是怎么变成我的吗？
Quinn, aren't you curious how you became me?
如果答案包括冲着主星里面飞过去的话
If that answers even involves flying into a sun,
我一点都不好奇  我觉得是个人都不会好奇的
I'm not curious. I don't think anybody's curious.
- 啊！   - 我很好奇！快说！
- Aah! - I'm curious! Keep going!
你非要这样吗  KVN？！
Must you, KVN?!
- 你非要这样吗？   - 嘿嘿嘿
- Must you?! - Hee-hee hoo.
- 告诉我   - 只有一个生物能帮到我们
- Tell me. - There's only one being who can help us.
那就是一个居住在“内空”的泰坦
A Titan who inhabits a realm
“内空”位于我们的次元和另一个次元之间
between our dimension and the next called Inner Space.
他在我人生的低谷找到了我
He came to me. At my lowest point.
结束了  全都结束了
It's over. Everything is over.
我来了  盖瑞
I'm coming, Gary.
这并非你的命运
This is not your fate.
我带来的不是癫狂  而是救赎
I offer not madness, but salvation.
我们能改变已经发生的事
We can change what has become.
怎么改变
How?
一台能时空转移的机器
A machine to traverse time.
你可以自己搭一台  我会帮你
You can construct it. With my help.
你是谁？
Who are you?
波罗
Bolo.
我是无疆的受害者之一
A fellow victim of Infinity.
我们就要复仇了
And now we fight back.
- 波罗是谁？   - 他是个泰坦
- Who's Bolo? - He's a Titan.
泰坦是乐于复仇的可怖生物
The Titans are terrible, vengeful creatures
他们用混沌污染了宇宙
who poison the universe with chaos.
每个泰坦都分治不同的国度
Each in charge of a different realm.
但其中一个打破了常规  那就是波罗
One broke ranks. Bolo.
他看到了更好的出路  因此封住了我们的次元
He saw there was a better way and sealed off our dimension
让我们免于受到终空的威胁
from the horrors of Final Space.
泰坦们群起而攻之  把他囚禁了
They took revenge and imprisoned him.
他是唯一能帮到我们的生物
He's the only one who can help.
这太可怕了
That's sick.
性感的老奎恩说得对
Older hot Quinn makes an excellent point.
如果波罗是唯一一个能帮我们的  我们只有这一个办法了
If Bolo's the only one that can help us, we've got no choice.
Chookity pok!
说得好  月饼
Well said, Mooncake.
让我们向着主星扎进去吧！
Let's fly through a sun!
哦我的天哪  真不敢相信我们竟然要这么做
Oh, my Lord, I cannot believe we are doing this.
跨次元调整相位的难度众人皆知
Dimension phasing is notoriously difficult.
为了去见波罗  我们只能光折
To see Bolo, we're going to have to lightfold
而且必须精确穿过主星的光圈
exactly through the sun's aperture.
哪怕只差了一度  我们也会坠火身亡
If we are off by even one degree, we burn up and die.
请大家坐好  这段旅程将会非常崎岖
Buckle up. This will be a bumpy ride.
来吧  HUE  带我们进去吧！
All right, H.U.E. Take us in!
正在进入主星日冕
Entering into the corona of the sun.
主星的热量把导航系统熔穿了
The heat of the sun has melted through the navigation system.
你需要手动飞越光圈
You will need to manually navigate it into the aperture.
- 好的  我会做到的   - 但你不是个好飞行员
- All right, I'll do it. - But you're not a good pilot.
多谢这么信任我  奎恩！
Thank you very much for believing in me, Quinn!
- 希望你别搞砸了   - 又来一句没营养的话！
- Please do not screw this up. - Okay, that's not helping!
保持专注  盖瑞  你一定要做到
Concentrate, Gary. You gotta do this.
就像穿针引线
Let's thread this needle.
快啊  快啊！
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
- 盖瑞！瞄准它！   - 我一定能瞄准！
- Gary! Center it! - I got this!
你一定能做到的！上啊  闪电侠盗！
You got this, Thunder Bandit!
你根本没做到好嘛！瞄准了！
No, you don't! Center it!
- 哦你吓到我了！我好怕！   - 瞄准它！
- Oh, you're scaring me! I'm scared! - Center it!
我好怕啊啊啊！
I'm very frightened!
- 盖瑞！   - 啊！
- Gary! - Aah!
哦我的天哪  我的天哪
Oh, my crap! Oh, my crap.
欢迎来到“内空”
Welcome to Inner Space.
我们运气不好  他... 好像睡着了
Just our luck. He's... asleep.
盖瑞  他已经睡了一万年了
Gary, he's been asleep for 10,000 years.
- 呃  那我们干嘛过来？   - 等着
- Well, then why are we here? - Wait for it.
等什...？
Wait for wha...
把我放出去！
Get me the hell out of here!
我们是跑到这位大哥的脑壳里了吗？
Did we just get sucked into dude's mind?
- 别担心  这很正常   - 我可不觉得这团
- Don't worry, that's normal. - I am not okay with this
太空棉花糖的冬日嘉年华哪里正常！
winter wonderland of cosmic cotton candy!
啊！啊！
Aah! Aah!
我要降落在这个小叶片上了
I'm just gonna put this down right on this little lily pad.
准备落地了
Oh, there we go.
哦  嘿  那有个人  嘿  嘿！
Oh, hey, there's a guy. Hey. Hey!
我感觉我们可能来错地方了
So, not sure we're in the right place,
- 不过我们...   - 你们迟到了！
- but we got this thing ... -  You're late!
- 迟到了？   - 是的  迟到了！
- Late? - Yes, late!
- 他已经等你们好几年了！   - 你像一个着火的巨型MM豆一样
- He's been waiting on you for years! - You're like a giant flaming M&M.
你是在冒犯我吗？！
Excuse me?! Are you giving me sass?!
呀！
Hyah!
哦  喵的  你刚是
Oh! Freaking...! Did you just
把你的小棍砸我脑袋上了吗？！啊！
whack me in the face with your stick?! Aah!
咱俩没法好好相处了
You and I are not gonna get along.
给我... 解释一下...
Explain... to me...
刚刚发生了什么
what just happened.
我们飞到了第二脑舱
We hopped over to brain chamber two.
飞？不不不不！
Hopped? No, no, no, no!
我们是被扔下来...
We were hurled ...
啊  怎么这么湿  我是在...？
Oh, there's moisture. Am I...?
我眼睛流血了！
I think my eyes are bleeding!
我的眼啊！流血了！流血了！
My eyes! Blood! Blood!
这才是第六脑舱
This is only Brain Chamber Six.
我们到了  第795脑舱
Here we are. Chamber number 795.
波罗的思维宫殿
Bolo's Mind Palace.
从这往后  只有一个人能进去
Beyond this point, only one of you may enter,
而且这个人早就被选好了
and it's already been pre-selected.
是你————！
Yooooou!
你是天选之人
You've been chosen.
容我再强调一次  早在你出生之前
But then again, you were already selected
你就已经被选出来了
before you were even born!
- 我们在这等你  盖瑞   - 你能做到的！
- We'll be here, Gary. - You got this!
KVN会照顾月饼的  因为KVN最乐于助人了
KVN will look after Mooncake, 'cause he's so helpful.
♪ 哦  宝贝  KVN拥有超能力 ♪
♪ Oh, baby, KVN's got the magic ♪
♪ 超能力也拥有KVN ♪
♪ And the magic's got KVN ♪
我不喜欢这个  这里的所有东西我都不喜欢
I don't like this. All this right here, I don't like.
你不能和月饼一起闲逛了
You're not hanging out with Mooncake.
你会把他带坏的  知道吗？我一点都不喜欢你
You're a bad influence. Okay? 'Cause I don't like you.
♪ 哦  宝贝  KVN拥有超能力  超能力也拥有KVN ♪
♪ Oh, baby, KVN's got the magic, and the magic's got KVN ♪
♪ KVN拥有超能力  超能力也拥有KVN ♪
♪ KVN's got the magic, and magic's got KVN ♪
- 你最讨厌了   - 祝你好运  盖瑞
- You're the worst. - Good luck, Gary.
走近点  盖瑞
Come forth, Gary.
哦我的天哪  成吧...
Oh, my gosh. Okay...
哦... 哦... 啊！
Ohh... Oh ... ah!
啊！好吧  这很新奇
Aah! Okay. This is new.
要想面对未来
In order to face what's ahead,
先要面对自己的内心
you need to face what's inside of you.
哦  看哪！
Oh, look!
- 那有个安全帽盖瑞！   - 你好！
- There's a Construction Hat Gary. - Hey!
那个是鹰脸盖瑞
There's an Eagle-Faced Gary.
嗨！
Hi!
- 饼干头盖瑞   - 你好啊  有事吗？
- Cookie-Headed Gary. - Hi. What's up?
哦天哪  小小小盖瑞
Oh, my gosh! Little Micro Gary.
- 嘿！   - 那是谁？
- Hey! - Who's that?
那是帅胡子盖瑞
That's the Amazing Mustache Gary.
盖瑞  你永远也长不出来这样的胡子的
Gary, you're never gonna be able to grow one of these.
浓密的  性感的小胡子
A thick, rich, luscious mustache.
啊  摸上去感觉好极了！
Hell yeah, that feels good!
没错  我一直长不出来小胡子
It's true. I've never been able to grow a mustache.
我多希望自己是块点心渣  这样我就能卡在胡子里了
I wish I was a crumb, so I could get caught in this.
你在干什么  小胡子盖瑞？
What are you doing, Mustache Gary?
我在用我的小梳子梳理我的小胡子！
Combing my Mustache with my Little Mustache Comb!
你永远不会知道这有多令人满足
But you'll never know the satisfaction of that.
哦  触感好极了！
Oh, it feels so gooooood!
唉  是的  我永远没法体验到了
Ugh, it's so true. I won't.
不  这又是啥？
Oh, no. What is this?
啊！发生了啥？
Aah! What's happening?!
你的焦虑即将吞噬你
Your anxiety is consuming you.
你知道你做不到的
You know you can't succeed.
因为我长不出小胡子？
Because I can't grow a 'stache?
正是如此
That's exactly why.
你不是什么英雄
You're no hero.
你父亲才是
Your father was.
你说对了  他自己也知道
You're right. He would've figured this out.
我很害怕  怕我没法
I'm scared there's no winning this,
在不损失朋友的条件下
that there's no way to close this breach
补上那个缺口
without losing my friends.
不要再来一遍这个了！
Okay. Let's not do that again!
一切进展都由真理而始
All progress begins with the truth.
我们没时间了
We're running out of time.
我需要立刻知道怎么补上缺口
I need to know right now how to close this breach.
我不知道答案  但他知道
I don't have the answer for you, but he will.
“他”又是谁？我可不认识“他”
Who the hell is "He Will?" I don't know a "He Will."
你只有一点点时间
You'll only have a short time.
有人吗？
Hello?
爸
Dad.
盖瑞那边什么情况？
What's going on with Gary?
- 他很好   - 把它们播出来  你个守门的
- He's fine. - Show them, Gatekeeper.
亮出你的秘密！如果你敢打我  我就杀了你
Reveal your secrets! And if you hit me, I will end you.
哦我的天哪！你们一个个的都太没礼貌了！
Oh, my gosh! You are all so sassy!
好好看着  让我一个人呆着
Just watch and leave me alone already.
月饼  循着我的声音过来
Mooncake, follow my voice.
Chockity.
KVN  别乱碰东西
KVN, stop touching stuff.
♪ 超能力也拥有KVN ♪ 一起来！
♪ And the magic's got KVN ♪ Everybody!
- 爸  是我  盖瑞   - “爸”？你小子谁啊？
- Dad, it's me, Gary. - Dad? Who the hell are you?
为什么时间静止了？你让时间静止了吗？
And why did time freeze? Did you freeze time?
你个静止时间的恶魔！
You time-freezing demon!
哇啊！好吧  我知道如果我告诉你
Whoa! Okay, look. I don't think you would
我是怎么过来的  你是不会信我的
believe me if I told you how I got here.
不过我的确要告诉你  我是你的儿子
But I'm telling you I am your son.
我儿子比你年轻多了  差不多是你一半的年纪
My son is much younger, a boy half your age.
你要真是我儿子  我们的承诺是什么？
If you're really my son, what was the promise?
- 什么承诺？   - 在我离开之前的承诺
- What? - Before I left.
我承诺我会经历自己的冒险  许许多多的冒险
To have my adventures. Bunches and bunches of them.
- 真的是你？   - 和你眼之所见一样真实  爸
- Is it really you? - As real as it gets, Dad.
天哪   太好了
Oh, hell yeah.
你到底来这干什么啊？
What the hell are you doing here?
这简直是天方夜谭  不过我真的在试着拯救地球...
It's a real novel, but I'm trying to save the Earth ...
其实说“拯救宇宙”会更酷  所以我从此以后
actually universe sounds way cooler, so I'm actually gonna say
- 就说“拯救宇宙”了   - 你说什么？
- "universe" from now on. - You're what?
我正在想办法修补一个宇宙里的缺口
I'm trying to find out how to close a breach in space
不然它会把地球给毁了的  呃  我的意思是
that will most certainly destroy Earth ...
它会把宇宙毁了的... 这些都发生在我的时间线上  老天哪
actually universe ... in my time. God, that sounds so cool.
我真的大声说出来了  感觉非常棒
I really feel cool saying that out loud.
呃  这其实是我现在正在做的事
Well, that's what I'm doing now!
- 你说什么？   - 你在做我正在做的事
- What? - You're doing what I'm doing.
- 我在做你正在做的事！   - 不是吧！
- I'm doing what you're doing! - No way!
- 你看啊   - 你也要修补太空缺口？
- Look! - You're closing the breach in space?
是啊  和我的飞行员同事一起
Me and my co-pilot, yeah.
- 他在这做什么？！   - 杰克是我的同事啊
- What is he doing here?! - Jack's my co-pilot.
我们一起做了很多年任务了
We've been doing missions together for years.
杰克？！这厮是总司令啊！
Jack?! This guy is the Lord Commander!
- 谁？   - 这家伙用脑电波把我胳膊扽下来了
- Who? - The guy who ripped my arm off
还杀了我最好的朋友
with his mind and killed my best friend.
杰克是我的同事  我们已经做了29年朋友了
Jack is my co-pilot. He's been my friend for 29 years.
不过我决定相信你的话
But I'll take your word for it.
儿子  你觉得咱俩把他海扁一顿怎么样？
Well, what do you say we beat the crap out of him, son?
你真是我亲爸
You are my dad.
好你个臭混蛋...
Hey! You sick sack of ...
啊！
Gah!
哈！嘿！
Ha! Heyyy!
嘿！照着脸一顿猛揍！
Heyyyyyy! Multiple punches in the face!
每个男孩都渴望着和他的父亲一起
Every boy dreams of building cherished memories...
- 再加点劲！   - ... 共同留下美好回忆
- Harder! - ...with his dad.
- 就像现在这样   - 把他踹死！
- Like this. - Kick him in the nuts!
像这样！
Oh, and this!
或者这样！
Oh, and these!
- 呀！   - 真是我的好儿子
-  Hyah! - That's my boy.
你上次见我是什么时候？
When was the last time you saw me?
就是这次任务之前
Right before this mission.
- 你再也没回来   - 嗯
- You never came back. - Hm.
- 所以我就快死了  是不是？   - 如果我能改变的话  你就不会死
- So, I'm about to die, huh? - Not if I can help it.
所以我们要怎么修补这个缺口？
So how are we gonna close this breach?
- 我需要知道   - 要在缺口的视界
- I need to know for me. - An anti-matter bomb detonated
引爆一个反物质炸弹
at the event horizon of the breach.
视界（event horizon）：黑洞的边界。
问题是  在你上船之前
The thing is, right before you came aboard,
一波从终空泄漏出来的能量波正要击中我们的船体
an energy blast in Final Space was about to hit our ship.
然后时间停滞了  所以没办法把炸弹送过去了
Time froze, and now there's no way to deliver the bomb.
- 除非...   - 打他一下
- Unless... - Hit me.
好的
Nice.
谢了  如果把炸弹手动送出去呢？
Thanks. What if you take out the bomb manually?
- 也许能行   - 真的？
- That could work. - Really?
哇  我觉得  我们可以一起弄
Wow, I mean, we could do it together.
月饼  该你出场了
Mooncake. It's time you knew.
哇  看看这些酷炫的脑组织
Whoa, look at all this cool brain stuff.
嗯  这是我的了  这也是我的  这也是
Hmm. That's mine, and that's mine, and that's mine.
嘿  拿这些脑子做果冻吧！
Hey, let's do Jell-O shots with the brain goo!
你是通往终空的钥匙
You're the key to Final Space...
因为你正是
because that's what you're made of.
由终空构成的
Final Space.
Chockity.
我们得把第一级和第二级扳机取出来
We'll need to take out the primary and secondary trigger.
是的  然而我不知道这些都是啥
Right. I have no idea what that is,
所以我就看着你弄  然后点头就好了
so I'm gonna look at you and nod in agreement.
- 所以  遇到你爱的人了吗？   - 还没  呃  其实算是遇到了
- So, you met anybody? - No, well, kind of.
我同时遇到了两个人... 但是
I'm seeing two people at the same time ... but mainly,
我没脚踏两只船  因为她俩是一个人
I'm not like cheating because they're the same person.
懂了  是时空穿梭？
Got it. Time-travel thing?
- 是的！   - 我也遇到过
- Yes! - Been there.
- 哈！   - 俩傻子
- Ha!  - Nice pair.
- 她们叫什么？   - 奎恩
- What's their name? - Quinn.
- 是什么样的人？   - 是那个年轻又性感的？
- What's she like? - The younger hot one?
- 还是那个年纪大了但依旧性感的？   - 你时间线里的那个
- Or the older equally hot one? - The one in your timeline.
呃  她很任性  但也很专注  是个真正的领袖
Well, she's headstrong, focused, and a real leader.
- 你爱她吗？   - 哦！
- Do you love her? - Ohh!
我爱她胜过一切
To the max-core.
但我觉得在她看来我什么都不是
But I don't think she thinks very much of me.
真的吗？你很有魅力的
Really? You're a catch.
你真觉得我有魅力？你... 真这么认为？
You think I'm a catch? You ... you think so?
当我看着你时  我看到了一个魅力十足的人
I'm looking at you, I'm seeing a catch.
好的  该出发了
All right, it's ready to go.
你确认没别的需要做的了？
You sure there isn't anything else that needs to be done?
炸弹方面的？或者关于其它东西的？
Bomb-wise? Anything else at all?
- 没有了  咱们走   - 咱们还可以一起吃个午饭呢
- That's it. Let's go. - We could get lunch.
你想一起吃个午饭吗？
You want to get lunch?
儿子  拿上等离子体炬
Son. Grab the plasma torch.
等离子体炬（plasma torch）：用来发出一束定向等离子体喷流的装置。
你要干什么  爸！
What are you doing? Dad!
爸  你不能一个人去！
Dad, don't do this without me!
儿子  你在你的时间线上还有事要做
Son, you have your own time to worry about.
爸！这是... 这是我的主意
Dad! This ... This was my idea.
没错  不过这是我的责任
Yeah, but it's my responsibility.
还有另外一个反物质炸弹在纽约  在地球上
There's another anti-matter bomb in New York. The one on Earth.
去找它  然后用它对付你时间线上的缺口
Use it to close this breach in your time.
其实  我离开时只有一件后悔的事
You know, I had only one regret when I left.
那就是  我以为我没有机会
Thought I was never gonna get the chance
看到长大成人的你了
to see the man you would've grown up to be.
不过现在我已经知道  他比我想象出的最好的样子的还要好
Well, now I know he's better than I would've ever hoped.
求求你... 别走  求你了
Please don't... Stop. Please.
别走  别走  别走！别走！
Stop. Stop. Stop! Stop!
求你了！不要走！
No! Please no! Stop!
我不会让你死的  再也不会了
I'm not gonna let you die. Not again.
我会去找你的！
I'm gonna come get you!
给我个承诺  儿子  去拯救地球吧
Make me a promise, son. Save the Earth.
啊  你说的对  “拯救宇宙”听起来酷多了
Nah, you're right. "Universe" sounds much cooler.
- 万一我做不到呢？   - 那就做到你的最好
- What if I can't do it? - Try your best.
万一我的最好都还不够好呢？
What if my best isn't good enough?
你的最好  对我来说已经足够好了
It's good enough for me.
- 不要————！   - 不
- Noooooooo! - No.
啊！
Aaah!
哦我的天哪！
Oh, God!
啊啊啊！
Aaaah!
为什么？
Why?
一直不知道咱俩同病相怜
Didn't know we were members of the same club.
盖瑞  你还要做这个吗？
Gary, you still want to do this?
- 我要做到我的最好   - 你的最好  对我来说已经足够好了
- I'll try my best. - That's good enough for me.
等等... 你刚是看了我和我爸吗？
Wait ... were you watching me and my dad?
没... 没有
No... No.
- 你去哪？   - 他们不再需要我了
- Where are you going? - They don't need me anymore.
- 咱该走了吗？   - 不  我们还有一点点时间
- Should we get up? - No. We have a little time.
其实你们没时间了！你们这些没礼貌的人  快给我滚！
Actually, you don't! Get off your sass buckets!
盖瑞  夜幕不一起来吗？
Gary, is Nightfall not coming with us?
不
No.
每当你觉得自己认识了一个人以后  类似这样的事就会发生
You think you know a person, and then something like this happens.
- 我们的航线要设向哪？   - 地球  哦不  其实是宇宙
- What course should I set? - Earth. Or actually, no, the Universe.
我们可是要拯救宇... 算了吧
We're gonna save the ... Well actually,
算了算了  说大话没用
well, that's doesn't even make any dang sense.
就设向地球吧  地球...
Okay, just Earth. Earth...
- 地球   - 我们要赶紧找炸弹去了
- Earth. - We've got a bomb to find.
Sync & Correction by f1nc0 from Addic7ed.com
幕后专访
INSIDE THE EPISODE
至于波罗的出现  我们想制造这样一个“好”的泰坦
With Bolo, the whole idea was to create this one good Titan,
制造一个有大智慧的生物
to create a creature that had great wisdom.
在盖瑞和他爸爸面对面对话那里  事情变得严肃起来
Things are trying to get serious, things are trying to get heating up,
剧情开始升温  那真是个苦乐参半的场景
when Gary actually has a conversation with his dad, such a bittersweet moment.
当你意识到盖瑞为他爸爸的死
You really feel the emotion, when you realize that he was
负有一定责任以后  你确实能感受到那种心情
part of the process of getting his dad killed.
对真人来说  光折进入主星会把他杀死的
When they lightfold into a sun, real person will probably die.
但在动画里  科学事实可以通融一下
In the animation, the science can bend the rules a little bit.
我们的目标完全是为了娱乐
We went straight for entertainment.